[Music]
it is only a few weeks until autumn is
officially here but i can already detect
a few subtle shifts in my world
the days are just a little cooler and we
finally have some rain
a few tentative leaves have started to
show the first apples of red and orange
a richness of color it's on its way and
will sweep over the valley at the end of
the month transforming the landscape and
kissing the tamarack trees with a gold
hue
i'm so excited for it
[Music]
however autumn isn't here quite yet but
there are things that i like to do in
september to prepare
i still have flowers in my garden but
since many will soon go to seed i'm
spending the next few weeks harvesting
what i need for my winter teas and herbs
and finishing any last art pieces that
i've been putting off
of course as a special summer
celebration for myself this morning i
decided to decorate my hair with fresh
flowers
if you've watched my other videos you
will know that i have a passion for
flowers and the only downside of autumn
is that i won't see them again until
next spring so i'm enjoying them while i
still can
[Music]
do
i will be honest with you this summer
has been tough on me i have even noticed
that my last few videos were far more
introspective than usual
i appreciate all of you who've been so
supportive during this time
with the approach of autumn i'm feeling
light and positive again hopeful for a
wonderful season of frost and rose hips
and fallen leaves
[Music]
so
i tend to read more books during the
darker months and i like to keep a
journal full of my observations and
ideas
i also like to decorate it with dried
leaves and plants and add some poems
that inspire me or that i have composed
myself
i'm not a professional journalmaker and
to be honest have little patience for it
i sometimes rush my steps to the
detriment to the end result but really
value having a special book that i made
myself where i can share my heart and
writing
[Music]
often our immediate inclination when we
want something new like a journal or
decorations for our home is to buy it
especially when items are so readily
available
and yet i think when it comes to highly
personal objects like diaries
making it can be a sort of peaceful
ceremony where we imbue our own love
into the process and come out of it with
something truly unique
maybe it doesn't have the perfection of
a factory produced item but it is a
product of our time and care it has a
story
i believe the same goes for decorations
i carefully consider each item i bring
into my home
often asking myself that if instead of
buying an item i could instead gain the
knowledge and experience of creating it
this october i will be making my own
broom some fall themed art for the walls
and other crafts
i'm very excited to work with my hands
and discover what i'm capable of i
encourage you to do so as well please
share it with me while i cannot respond
to all my messages i still love to see
what you're working on
[Music]
bringing in the harvest and foraging any
last little bits of plants and berries
is something i always do in early
september
this day i was looking for huckleberries
which is a fascinating plant that is
native to this region
it is a great source of nutrients and
can be used in a variety of different
ways
berries can be made into syrups and teas
and cakes
huckleberries prefer to grow in
mountainous areas for example in a basin
like this you can find them covering
most of the ground they are so abundant
it's hard not to crush juicy berries
underfoot as you walk
that's why in late summer when the first
rain softens the mossy rocks and trails
i like to walk barefoot the wet earth
feels so comforting under my feet
one of my favorite things about the
huckleberry is that it doesn't like to
be tamed
growing it in a more domestic garden is
very difficult and it prefers to be wild
living its natural cycle among the
mountain peaks
i find this little berry very inspiring
it makes me wonder if all of us have a
little wild streak
something more primitive that doesn't
quite fit into the mundane world
i think that the undomesticated side of
me is what brings me up to these
mountains time and again to reap the
harvest of the wild lands
i think we all have a wild side
one that cannot be controlled and maybe
that's a good thing
if we listen to it it calls us out into
nature to preserve the magic in this
world
[Music]
so
please let me know what you love to do
in order to prepare for autumn
i'm so looking forward to this time of
the year and i'm excited to share it
with you
my valley looks so different in october
and it's just magical i hope you have a
wonderful day or night and take care
sending you my love
[Music]
you